

ABOUT ME

Maritime industry professional with approximately 2 years of experience, now transitioning to a career in software development. Bringing strong problemsolving skills, attention to detail, and a passion for technology to contribute effectively in the software development field. Currently enhancing programming skills through hands-on projects and formal education.

CONTACT

Address:

Village – Bhopatpur, P.O. – Jogapur Kothi, P.S. – Jamo Bazar District – Siwan State – Bihar Pin Code – 841413

Mobile No.:

+91 9461292385

Email:

9697rahul@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/rahul-kumar-15b440171

GitHub

https://github.com/ra-h-u-l

HOBBIES

- Swimming
- Cricket
- Badminton

RAHUL KUMAR

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

Diploma in Programming (May 2023 – September 2024) CGPA –

Indian Maritime University, Kolkata Campus

B. Tech. – Marine Engineering (August 2016 – June 2020) Aggregate – 77.96 %

Shakti Shanti Academy, Chapara, Bihar

Senior School Certificate Examination | CBSE | 2015 Aggregate – 80.8 %

D.A.V. Centenary Public School, Siwan, Bihar

Secondary School Examination | CBSE | 2013 CGPA – 9.8

PROJECT

1) Library Management System – an online e-library

Developed an online Library Management System using Flask for the backend, Vue.js for the frontend, and SQLite for the database. Implemented features like user authentication, book search, and e-book purchasing. Overcame challenges related to performance optimization and database management.

URL - https://github.com/ra-h-u-I/LMSv2

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript
- Web Technologies: Flask, VueJs, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Database Management: PostgreSQL

WORK EXPERIENCE (NON-CODING)

Valad Infotech Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai

Designation: Project Engineer

June 2022 – April 2024

- Handled PMS (Planned Maintenance System) based on ABS Nautical System Enterprises (NSE) software for operating vessels.

A.G. Maritime Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai

Designation: Engine Cadet (Training)

August 2021 - February 2022

- Sailed on Roll-on/Roll-off vessel and learnt about the operation and maintenance of various marine machineries and systems.